-Good morning, Miss Ratched.  -Good morning.
-Good morning, Miss Ratched.  -Mr. Washington.
-Good morning, Bancini.  -Good morning.
How are you feeling?
Rested.
Medication time.
Okay, move it up!
Mr. Fredrickson, here.
Juice.
Chief.
Okay, my friend, let's go.
Here's his papers, and I'm gonna need a signature.
Hi.
-Mr. McMurphy's here.  -All right.
All right, I'm ready.
Okay. One pair of socks.
T-shirt.
Hi.
Goddamn, boy, you're as big as a mountain.
Look like you might have played some football.
What's your name?
He can't hear you. He's deaf.
Deaf and dumb Indian.
Is that so?
Come on, Bibbit.
Can't even make a sound, huh?
How?
Club lead. Jack of clubs.
What's your name, son?
Billy Bibbit.
Glad to know you, Bill. McMurphy's mine.
That's old Charlie Cheswick's cards.
That's his ace of spades.
Your turn, Bill.
-Put one of them on it, will you?  -Wait a minute.
Oh, I can win that one. I win.
Oh, you overtrumped?
Sure.
Pinochle, Bill? For any spades?
What's the bid?
Five... Five-fifty.
You like to look at other people's cards, do you?
Yes.
Ever seen this one?
-Come on, Martini.  -Martini!
Martini, will you? Will you play a club?
Whose turn is it now?
Well, let's see, he trumped...
Where you going?
-Aren't you gonna play?  -What's the matter with him?
Aren't you gonna play, Martini?
Martini? I wanna play.
Billy, I wanna win some...
Get a grip on yourself, will you?
Yes?
Mr. McMurphy's here, Doc.
Good, have him come in.
Thank you.
McMurphy, I'm Dr. Spivey.
Dr. Spivey, what a pleasure it is to meet you.
Sure. Pull up a chair, sit down and let's talk.
Sure.
R.P. McMurphy.
That's a hell of a fish there, Doc.
-Isn't that a dandy?  -Yeah.
It's about 40 pounds, ain't it?
-No, 32.  -Thirty-two...
But I'll tell you,
it took every bit of strength I had to hold it out there...
while the guy took the picture.
Every damn bit.
Probably that chain didn't help it any, either.
You didn't weigh the chain, did you, Doc?
No, I didn't weigh the chain.
But I'll tell you, I'm awfully proud of that picture.
That's the first Chinooker I ever caught.
It's a nice one.
Randall Patrick McMurphy.
Thirty-eight years old.
What can you tell me about...
Why you've been sent over here?
I don't know.
What's it say there?
-Mind if I smoke?  -No, go right ahead.
Well, it says several things here.
Said you'd been belligerent.
Talked when unauthorized.
You've been resentful in attitude toward work, in general. That you're lazy.
Chewing gum in class.
Well, the real reason that you've been sent over here...
is because they wanted you to be evaluated.
To determine whether or not you're mentally ill.
This is the real reason.
Why do you think they might think that?
Well, as near as I can figure out, it's cause I...
fight and fuck too much.
In the penitentiary?
No, no, no, you mean why...
Why did you get sent over here...
from the work farm?
Well, I really don't know, Doc.
It says here that you went around...
-Let me just take a look...  -It ain't up to me, you know.
You've got at least...
five arrests for assault.
What can you tell me about that?
Five fights, huh?
Rocky Marciano's got 40, and he's a millionaire.
-That's true.  -That is true.
Of course, it's true that you went in for...
statutory rape.
That's true, is it not, this time?
Absolutely true. But, Doc...
she was 15 years old going on 35, Doc...
and she told me she was 18, and she was...
very willing, you know what I mean?
I practically had to take to sewing my pants shut.
But between you and me...
she might have been 15. When you get that little red beaver...
right up there in front of you, I don't think it's crazy at all.
And I don't think you do, either.
I hear what you're saying.
No man alive could resist that. That's why I got into jail to begin with.
And now they're telling me I'm crazy over here...
Cause I don't sit there like a goddamn vegetable.
It don't make a bit of sense to me.
If that's what being crazy is...
Then I'm senseless, out of it, gone down the road, whacko...
but, no more, no less. That's it.
To be honest with you, McMurphy what it says here...
is that...
they think...
you've been faking it in order to get out of your work detail.
What do you think about that?
Do I look like that kind of guy to you?
Let's just be frank for a minute. All right, Randall, if you would.
Tell me...
Do you think there's anything wrong with your mind, really?
Not a thing, Doc.
I'm a goddamn marvel of modern science.
You're gonna be here for a period for us to evaluate you.
We're gonna study you.
We'll make our determinations as to what we're going to do...
and give you the necessary treatment as indicated.
Doc, let me just tell you this.
I'm here to cooperate with you 100 percent.
A hundred percent.
I'll be just right down the line with you. You watch.
Cause I think we ought to get to the bottom of...
R.P.McMurphy.
The scythe.
I'm awfully tired.
Sit down.
I'm tired.
Is that better?
Mr. Ellsworth...
you'll wear yourself out.
All right, gentlemen, let's begin.
At the close of Friday's meeting...
we were discussing Mr. Harding's problem concerning his wife.
Mr. Harding stated that his wife made him uneasy...
because she drew stares from men on the street.
Is that correct, Mr. Harding?
Yes.
That's correct.
He also thinks he may have given her reason...
to seek sexual attention elsewhere, but he wasn't able to say how.
Mr. Harding has been heard to say to his wife:
"I hate you."
"I don't ever want to see you again."
"You've betrayed me."
So, does anyone care to touch on this further?
Mr. Scanlon, would you begin today?
Are you sure?
Billy, how about you?
No, no, ma'am.
I'd like to write in my book that you began the meeting.
Just once.
Mr. Martini?
Are you with us?
Yes.
Would you like to begin?
Mr. Cheswick?
-Me?  -Yes.
You mean there's not a man here who has an opinion on this matter?
All right.
Mr. Harding...
you've stated on more than one occasion...
that you suspected your wife of seeing other men.
Oh, yes!
Yes, very much, I suspect her.
I suspect her.
Maybe you can tell us why...
you suspect her.
Well, I can only...
speculate as to the reasons why.
Have you ever speculated, Mr. Harding...
that perhaps you are...
impatient with your wife...
because she doesn't meet your mental requirements?
Perhaps. But you see, the only thing I can really...
speculate on, Nurse Ratched...
is the very existence of my life...
with or without my wife...
in terms of the human relationships, the juxtaposition of...
one person to another, the form, the content.
Harding, why don't you knock off the bullshit and get to the point?
This is the point.
This is the point, Taber. It's not bullshit.
I'm not just talking about my wife, I'm talking about my life!
I can't seem to get that through to you.
I'm not just talking about one person,
I'm talking about everybody!
I'm talking about form! I'm talking about content!
I'm talking about interrelationships!
I'm talking about God, the Devil, Hell, Heaven!
Do you understand? Finally?
Yeah, Harding, you're so fucking dumb I can't believe it.
It makes me feel very peculiar, very peculiar...
-when you throw in something like that.  -Why?
What does that mean, "peculiar," Harding?
-Peculiar?  -Peculiar?
I'm gonna tell you guys something.
You just don't want to learn anything.
You just don't want to listen to anybody.
He's got intelligence!
You've never heard the word "peculiar"?
Say, what are you trying to say?
You trying to say I'm queer? Is that it?
Little Mary Ann? Little Marjorie Jane?
Is that it? Is that what you're trying to tell me?
Is that your idea of communicating something to me? Is it?
Well, is it?
They're all crowding in on you, Mr. Harding.
They're all ganging up on you.
Is that news?
They sometimes want to gang up on me, too, but I...
Cheswick, do me a favor.
Take it easy.
-And stay off my side.  -But I only wanna...
I only wanna help you.
-I understand.  -But don't you want me to...?
-Please!  -But I only want to...
-Please!  -But I only want to help you.
Please!
You see...
the other day you made some allusions, both of you....
-Illusions?  -Yes, allusions.
Not illusions. Allusions...
to sexual problems I might be having with my wife.
All right, let's say it's true! Let's say I know it to be true.
But you don't!
If that's your idea of trying to tell me something,
you have another...
You know, Harding,
I think you're some kind of morbid asshole or something!
-Peculiar!  -Asshole again.
It makes you feel peculiar.
You've been talking about your wife ever since I can remember!
You know, she's on your mind, and blah, blah, blah...
I'm not talking about my wife!
When are you gonna get that through your thick fucking head?
When are you gonna wise up and turn her loose?
-Please!  -I don't want to hear it!
-I'm tired.  -I don't want to hear it!
I'm tired...
I don't want to hear it...
It's a lot of baloney and I'm tired.
I don't want to hear it!
We know you're tired. We're all tired.
I'm tired and it's a lot of baloney.
You're not tired, Bancini.
Take your hands off me!
Recreation time, gentlemen.
The bus is waiting.
All nonrestricted patients please report to the bus.
Ever play this game, Chief?
Come on, I'll show you.
Old Indian game.
It's called "put the ball in the hole."
Now, that ought to be just...Hold it right there.
All right.
Now, that's your spot. Don't move.
Never move. That's your spot, you understand?
Right there. You don't move. Now...
take the ball.
Here, take the ball.
That's it. Hold on to it.
Not too hard, Chief. You'll crush all the air out of it.
We're gonna put her in the basket. You understand?
All right. Now, raise up your arms.
Raise the ball up in the air, Chief. Raise it up.
McMurphy?
What the hell are you talking to him for? He can't hear a fucking thing.
I ain't talking to him. I'm talking to myself.
It helps me think.
Yeah, well, it don't help him none.
Well, it don't hurt him, either, does it?
Don't hurt you, does it, Chief?
See? Don't hurt him.
All right, now, Chief...
Let's raise our hands up in the air.
Just raise them up.
Up, you understand?
Raise the hands up, here.
Up. Raise your hands up.
Up! That's it! That's it! Up, all the way up.
All the way up. That's a baby, all right.
Okay, now...
Now, jump up in the air, and put it in the basket, Chief.
Jump up and dunk it in!
Jump up in the air and stuff that son of a bitch in there, Chief.
Take a rest, Chief.
Just stay right there. Take a rest. I'll be right back.
Bancini, come here for a minute.
You're looking all right. Get right over here for a second.
Now, just stand right there.
Just get down a little bit. All right. Stand up.
Stand up. Go ahead.
That's a baby! All right, you got her.
All right. Now, over there.
Hit me, Chief! I got the moves! I got them, Chief!
Hold it right there. Give me the ball.
Give me the ball. That's it. Thank you, Chief.
Now...
hold it right there.
You take the ball, you jump up, and put it in the basket.
See what I mean? Put it... Bancini, hold still.
All right, Chief, here. Take the ball.
Now, jump up and put her in the basket, Chief!
Jump up and put her in the basket!
Not you, Bancini.
Raise up! Bancini, where you going?
I'm tired!
Fast break! Defense! Get back!
Come on, Bancini, where the fuck you going at?
General, get this man around here.
That's it, back!
Over to Chief.
Fast break! Fast break! Hit me, Chief!
Hit me, baby!
Put it in the basket, Chief!
Put it in the basket!
All right.
Make the bets.
What's this?
It's a dime, Martini.
I bet a nickel.
A dime's the limit, Martini.
I bet a dime.
This is not a dime, Martini.
This is a dime.
If you break it in half...
you don't get two nickels, you get shit.
Try and smoke it. You understand?
You don't understand! All right, here they come.
Queen to the Chesser, big bull to Tabulations...
ten to Billy to match his whang, and the dealer gets a three.
Hit me. Hit me.
I can't hit you because it ain't your turn yet. You understand?
You see these other people? These are the real ones.
These are real people here.
What'll you do, Ches? Hit or sit?
Hit me.
That's 23 up, Cheswick.
Taber, you're busted. Give me this.
-Hit me.  -Shut up!
Taber.
-Give me a dime!  -I'm next. Taber.
You're not next!
Hit me.
-Ace.  -Hit me.
That's 4 or 14.
Don't want any more. Billy?
-Hit me. Hit me.  -Five.
You didn't make a bet, Martini. I can't hit you. Jesus Christ.
I bet a dime.
All right, here.
-That's 20 showing.  -No.
-Take your money.  -No.
It's not.
It's 10, 11, 12, 13.
This is a fucking queen here, you understand?
You don't count the this and the this.
Hit me.
You got 20 showing!
Hit me again. I want another card.
Scanlon, who's pitching the opener?
Medication time.
This isn't a queen!
Mac, hit me.
-Who's pitching the opener?  -Hit me.
Jesus Christ Almighty!
Do you nuts wanna play cards or you wanna fucking jerk off?
Play the game!
I can't even hear myself think already, here.
Stay back!
-Excuse me, ma'am. I just wanted to...  -Stay back!
Patients aren't allowed in the nurses' station.
Well, I just wanted to turn...
When you're outside, we'll discuss whatever problem you have, okay?
The patients are not allowed in the nurses' station. All right?
Let me get in here, will you, Hard-on? Thank you.
Excuse me, miss.
Do you think it might be possible to turn that music down...
so maybe a couple of the boys could talk?
That music is for everyone, Mr. McMurphy.
Yeah, I know, but do you think we might ease it down a little bit...
so maybe the boys didn't have to shout?
What you probably don't realize...
is that we have a lot of old men on this ward...
who couldn't hear the music if we turned it lower.
That music is all they have.
Your hand is staining my window.
-I'm sorry, ma'am.  -All right.
Mr. McMurphy, your medication.
What's in the horse pill?
It's just medicine. It's good for you.
Yeah, but I don't like the idea of taking something
if I don't know what it is.
Don't get upset, Mr. McMurphy.
I'm not getting upset, Miss Pilbow.
It's just that I don't want anyone to try and slip me saltpeter.
You know what I mean?
It's all right, Nurse Pilbow.
If Mr. McMurphy doesn't want to take his medication orally...
I'm sure we can arrange that he can have it some other way.
But I don't think you'd like it, Mr. McMurphy.
You'd like it, wouldn't you, Hard-on?
Give it to me.
Good.
Very good!
Yummy!
Mr. Harding?
Merci.
Tell me, Lover-boy...
why didn't you tell her to go fuck herself?
Jesus Christ.
Funny, huh? That's funny, huh?
you know that wasn't very smart. She could have seen that.
God Almighty, she's got you guys coming and going.
What do you think she is? Some kind of a champ or something?
No, I thought you were the champ.
You want to bet?
Bet on what?
One week.
I bet in one week I can put a bug so far up her ass...
she won't know whether to shit or wind her wrist watch.
What do you say to that? Wanna bet? Do you wanna bet?
One week. That's all I need. Who wants to bet?
You wanna bet? Bet a buck. One buck.
I'll bet.
Tabes in, one buck. Solid.
Last time we were discussing...
Mr. Harding and the problem with his wife...
and I think we were making a lot of progress.
So who would like to begin today?
Mr. McMurphy?
I've been thinking about what you said about...
you know, getting things off your chest.
Well, there's a couple of things that I'd like to get off my chest.
Well, that's very good, Mr. McMurphy. Go ahead.
Today, as you may or may not know, it doesn't matter...
is the opening of the World Series.
What I'd like to suggest is that we change the work detail tonight...
so that we can watch the ball game.
Well, Mr. McMurphy, what you're asking...
is that we change a very carefully worked out schedule.
A little change never hurt, huh?
A little variety?
Well, it's not necessarily true, Mr. McMurphy.
Some men on the ward
take a long, long time to get used to the schedule.
Change it now, and they might find it very disturbing.
Fuck the schedule!
They can go back to the schedule after the Series.
I'm talking about the World Series, Nurse Ratched.
Well, anyway, this is no way to proceed about this.
How would it be if we had a vote...
and let majority rule?
Great. Let's vote on her.
So, all those in favor raise your hands.
Okay, guys, come on.
Put your hands up.
What's the matter with you? Don't you want to watch the World Series?
Come on, get your hands up. It can do you some good...
to get some exercise, putting your arms up in the air.
That's it. Come on, let's...
What is this crap?
I watch the Series. I haven't missed the Series in years.
Even in the cooler.
When I'm in the cooler they run it there or they'll have a riot.
What's the matter with you guys? Come on, be good Americans!
Well, Mr. McMurphy, I only count three votes, and...
that's not enough to change the ward policy.
I'm sorry.
-My turn.  -Okay, hot dice.
I want a ten to go...
Cause I need cash.
I wanna get to Mediterranean Avenue.
Big ten! Perfect.
Two fives.
-What are you doing?  -Hotel.
-You do not have a hotel there.  -Hotel.
For the third time...
you do not have a hotel on Boardwalk.  -Hotel.
-It costs $1,000 and four green houses...  -Hotel.
-to put a hotel on Boardwalk.  -Hotel.
Play the game and knock off the bullshit.
Play the game, Harding.
What are you talking about? I am playing the game.
Play the game!
I ain't doing anything to you!
-What bullshit?  -Your bullshit!
-What about your bullshit?  -Come on, play the game!
-Listen, you keep your hands off me!  -Play the game.
I've had enough bullshit out of you. You hear me?
-Play the game.  -What the fuck are you picking on me for?
Play the game, Harding.
-Look, I'm trying to ignore you, see?  -Just play the game.
Keep your hands off me, you son of a bitch!
Keep your hands off me! You hear me?
-Come on, come on.  -I can be pushed just so far, see!
Play the game.
You touch me once more. Just touch me once more.
Just once more, huh? Just once more.
-Just touch me once more.  -Play the game, Harding!
Just touch me once more!
Holy Jesus!
Is that what your schedule does for you, Hard-on?
Damn lunatic!
I don't know what you're talking about.
No? Well, then stay all wet, Harding, huh?
Cause I'm going downtown and watch the World Series, anyway.
Anybody want to come with me?
I do, Mac. I wanna go with you!
Ches, all right. Anybody else?
-Where?  -Any bar downtown.
Mac, you can't...
can't get out of here.
Anybody want to bet?
Chicken shits!
Maybe he'll just show Nurse Ratched his big thing...
and she'll open the door for him.
Yeah, maybe I will...
and then maybe I'll just use your thick skull
and knock a hole in the wall.
Sefelt, see?
Why? My head would squash like an eggplant.
Fuck Sefelt's head, I don't need Sefelt's head!
I'm gonna take this fucking thing,
I'll put it through the window...
and me and my buddy Cheswick are gonna go out through the hall...
downtown, sit down in a bar, wet our whistles...
and watch the ball game.
And that's the bet. Now, does anybody want any of it?
You're gonna lift that thing?
Yeah! That's right.
I'll bet a buck.
Taber, $1.
I bet a dime.
Mac, you can't...
can't lift that thing.
Anybody else want any of it? Hard-on?
I'll bet $25!
$25, Hard-on!
Mac, nobody could ever lift that thing.
Get out of my way, son. You're using my oxygen.
You know what I mean?
Giving up?
No! Just warming up.
Warming up.
This will be the one.
All right, baby.
But I tried, didn't I? Goddammit!
At least I did that.
And on the mound, the left-hander, Al Downing.
The two pitchers still warming up, right down below us.
The second game of the 1963 World Series...
is being brought to you from Yankee Stadium.
Did you tell the girl how you felt about her?
I went over to her house...
one Sunday afternoon and...
and I brought her some flowers...
and I said...
Celia, will you...
marry me?
Billy.
Why did you want to marry her?
Well, I was in love with her.
Your mother told me that you never told her about it.
Billy.
Why didn't you tell her about it?
Wasn't that the first time you tried to commit suicide?
Oh, my God!
Yes, Mr. Cheswick?
Miss Ratched...
I'd like to ask you a question, please.
Go ahead.
You know, if...
Billy doesn't feel like talking...
I mean, why are you pressing him?
Why can't we go on to some new business?
The business of this meeting, Mr. Cheswick...
is therapy.
You know, I don't understand this, Miss Ratched...
because I don't...
Mr. McMurphy...
He said something yesterday about a World Series.
A baseball game?
You know, and I've never been to a baseball game and...
I think I'd like to see one.
That would be good therapy, too, wouldn't it, Miss Ratched?
I thought we'd decided that issue.
I don't think so, because, I mean...
we discussed that yesterday...
and we have a new game today, I think, don't we, Mac?
That's right, Ches, and we want a new vote on it, don't we?
Would one more vote satisfy you, Mr. McMurphy?
Yeah.
It'll satisfy me.
There's a vote before the group.
Everyone in favor of changing the schedule, please raise your hand.
Okay, I want to see the hands. Come on!
Which one of you nuts has got any guts?
All right. That's it!
I only count nine votes, Mr. McMurphy.
She only counts nine. Only nine! It's a landslide.
There are 18 patients on this ward, Mr. McMurphy...
and you have to have a majority to change ward policy.
So you gentlemen can put your hands down.
Are you trying to tell me that you're gonna count these?
These poor sons of bitches, they don't know what we're talking about.
Well, I have to disagree with you, Mr. McMurphy.
These men are members of the ward, just as you are.
All right. All I need is one vote, right?
Right?
All right.
Want to watch the World Series?
Come on in, pal. This could be a big moment for you.
You wanna watch a baseball game?
You wanna watch baseball?
Just raise that hand up. Just raise the hand up.
-What do you say? I gave it all to her.
Sorry.
Bancini, old horse.
What do you say? You wanna watch the ball game on TV?
Wanna watch the ball game? Baseball? World Series?
What do you say, pal? You're tired?
Just raise your hand up, Bancini. Watch the ball game, huh?
I'm tired. Awfully tired.
Okay. All right.
What about you, pal?
All we need's one vote. Just one vote.
Just your one vote. That's all we need.
Just raise your hand up and your buddies can watch the baseball game.
General, you remember, don't you?
October, the banner, the stars...
"Oh, say can you..."
The World Series. Raise your hand up, Gen.
Just raise your hand up.
What about you pal, huh? Wanna watch the ball game?
Wanna watch the ball game, huh? Just one vote. Just raise your...
Gentlemen, the meeting is adjourned.
For Christ's sake, isn't there one of you fucking maniacs...
that knows what I'm talking about?
Mr. McMurphy?
The meeting is adjourned.
All right, just wait a minute, will you? Just one minute?
You can bring the subject up again tomorrow.
All right, Chief...
you're our last chance. What do you say?
Just raise your hand up.
That's all we need from you today, Chief.
Just raise your hand up one time.
Show her that you can do it.
Show her that you can still do it.
Just raise your hand up. All the guys have got them up.
Just raise your hand up, Chief. Will you? Huh?
Come on, there's got to be one guy here that's not a total fucking nut!
Mac?
Chief! The Chief!
Nurse Ratched? Nurse Ratched, look!
Look. The Chief put his hand up.
The Chief put his hand up. Look, he voted.
Would you please turn the television set on?
The Chief has got his hand up, right there.
The Chief voted. Now...
will you please turn the television set on?
Mr. McMurphy...
the meeting was adjourned, and the vote was closed.
But the vote was ten to eight.
The Chief, he's got his hand up! Look!
No, Mr. McMurphy.
When the meeting was adjourned, the vote was nine to nine.
Come on, you're not gonna say that now!
You're not gonna say that now!
You're gonna pull that henhouse shit, now, when the vote...
The Chief just voted! It was ten to nine!
I want that television set turned on! Right now!
Koufax...
Koufax kicks. He delivers.
It's up the middle, it's a base hit.
Richardson's rounding first! He's going for second!
The ball's in to deep right center!
Davidson, over in the corner, cuts the ball off!
Here comes the throw. Richardson's around the dirt!
He slides, he's in there. He's safe! It's a double!
He's in there, Martini! Look at Richardson, he's on second base.
Koufax is in big fucking trouble! Big trouble, baby!
All right, here's Tresh. He's the next batter!
Tresh looks in. Koufax...
Koufax gets the sign from Roseboro!
He kicks once, he pumps...
It's a strike!
Koufax's curve ball is snapping off like a fucking firecracker.
Here he comes with the next pitch.
Tresh swings! It's a long fly ball to deep left center!
It's going! It's gone!
Somebody give me a fucking wiener before I die.
It's the great Mickey Mantle, now! Here comes the pitch!
Mantel swings!
It's a fucking home run!
Gentlemen, stop this.
Stop this immediately.
Do you like it here?
That fucking nurse, man!
What do you mean, sir?
She ain't honest.
Miss Ratched's one of the finest nurses we've got in this institution.
Well, I don't wanna break up the meeting or nothing...
but she's something of a cunt, ain't she, Doc?
How do you mean that?
She likes a rigged game, you know what I mean?
Well, you know, I've been observing you here now...
for the last four weeks...
and I don't see any evidence of mental illness, at all.
I think that you've been trying to put us on, all this time.
You know, what do you want me to do? You know.
You know what I mean? Is that it?
Is that crazy enough for you?
Want me to take a shit on the floor? Christ!
Have you ever heard the old saying, "A rolling stone gathers no moss"?
Yeah.
Does that mean something to you?
It's the same as "Don't wash your dirty underwear in public."
I'm not sure I understand what you mean.
I'm smarter than him, ain't I?
Well, that sort of has always meant...
it's hard for something to grow on something that's moving.
How did you feel about what happened yesterday?
I want to kill...I mean...
Do you gentlemen have any more questions?
I don't have any more, but perhaps you do.
Do you have a question, McMurphy?
Where do you suppose she lives?
Chief, come on with me.
We'll show these guys who's nuts.
All right, wait.
Stand right here.
All right. Grab the fence.
Grab the fence here.
Right here, Chief. Strong!
Strong, like this, here.
That's it. All right.
Okay. Up.
That's it.
Fine, you got it.
All right, push!
Come on, Bob!
Where are you going?
Don't breathe on me, Club. Keep moving. Keep moving.
Come on, you guys. Get the lead out, huh?
Hey, what the hell's going on here?
Wait a minute!
Hold it!
See how easy it is?
Boys.
This here is Candy.
Candy, this is the boys.
You all crazies?
Let's go. Down here.
-Isn't this wonderful?  -Down here.
No problem.
Right here.
Come on, we don't want to be late for our first day out.
Hello!
Come on, will ya's? What are you standing around for here?
Get on board. Give them these, Candy.
Hey, wait a minute! What the heck is going on here?
What are you doing on this boat?
We're going fishing.
No, you're not going fishing.
Not on this boat. You're not going fishing on this boat.
Oh, yeah, on this boat. Ask Captain Block.
-Captain Block?  -Captain Block. Yes, that's right.
Who are you?
We're from the...
State Mental Institution...
This is Dr. Cheswick...
Dr. Taber, Dr. Fredrickson...
Dr. Scanlon.
The famous Dr. Scanlon.
Mr. Harding, Dr. Bibbit...
Dr. Martini, and...
Dr. Sefelt.
How about you? Who are you?
I'm Dr. McMurphy. R.P. McMurphy.
Wait, wait... Wait one second.
You don't understand. We chartered the boat.
We're going to go fishing.
And that's all there is to it.
You better quit on this.
They'll throw you in the can again, you know?
No, they won't. We're nuts!
They'll just take us back to the feeb farm, see?
Von Sefelt, get the stern line.
Tabes, you're at the bow.
This one?
That one! The one at your feet.
Get back on! Jesus!
Cheswick!
Come here, quick!
Aye, aye, sir. I mean, yes, Mac!
Take it easy, Charlie. Have you ever driven one of these things?
-Driven one of...  -Yeah.
No, Mac.
Well, it's a lot of fun.
Come on over here. Put your hands on the wheel.
-Put your hands on.  -I've never done this.
Put your hands on the wheel so you don't fall down. All right.
Just hold it steady right there, like that.
-Steady?  -Steady, yeah.
Now just go straight.
-Straight as an arrow, Charlie.  -Straight, Mac?
-Just straight. That's right.  -But, Mac...
Mac, this thing ain't too steady.
-Where are we going, Mac?  -Straight.
Just go on!
This is the bait.
Little fishes.
Dead fishes.
That's right.
Now what are we gonna do with these little fishes?
-Catch big fishes.  -That's right. That's right, Mr. Martini.
Hooks.
Now, hold on to your hooks...
Cause here are the fishes.
Tabes.
Get a fish here.
There, for you, Martini.
All right, now we each one of us has got a fish.
What are you laughing at, Martini?
You're not an idiot, huh?
You're not a goddamn looney now, boy, you're a fisherman.
Now, take your bottom hook.
You got it?
You take it...
and you...
push it all the way through.
Like that.
Wait a second. Get it through the eyes, here.
-Right through here.  -In the eye?
Don't worry about it! He's dead, Martini.
Jesus Christ, just put it through his eyeball, here.
That's it.
Crunch it right through. All right. Now you got it, see?
Now, you just pull that baby through. You see what I mean?
And you wrap it around. You pull this so it's a little loop.
That's very good.
That's very good, Mr. Fredrickson!
Very good eye work.
Good eye work.
That little devil's gonna not even feel the sting, is he, boy?
That son of a gun is gonna bite on you, isn't he?
You got beautiful hair.
Thank you.
And you got...
beautiful eyes.
Thank you.
Billy, what's the matter? Fishing don't grab you?
They do.
Now, come on with me, over here.
I'm gonna give each and every one of ya's a rod.
All right.
Here's your poles.
Now, just keep watching the tip here. If you get a strike, let me know.
Understand?
Come on, Candy. Just keep fishing, guys!
Don't call me unless you get something really big...
you can't handle yourselves.
Keep on fishing!
That's right.
Where is everybody?
Cheswick! Goddamn it, I told you to...
steer that boat straight!
Fish! Help, help!
Goddamn it, he's got a fish.
Hold it! Wait a minute, Tabes. I got it!
Cheswick, get the fuck back up there! Get up there in front!
Tabes, I got it, Tabes!
Get up, Tabes, I'll get it for you!
Son of a bitch, he's going over here! Get up there!
I got it!
-I got it!  -Give it to me!
Hey, Harding, I'm the skipper of this boat.
Shut up!
He said to go straight out as an arrow.
You're not going straight, you're kind of...
I'm going straight enough. Now, Chessy, stop it!
-It's my duty!  -Chessy, stop it!
No, you son of a bitch!
All right, Martini.
All right, take him over!
Take him over!
That's it! Now play them, boys!
You sons of bitches!
Keep it straight!
Come back this way!
Home safe and sound. Didn't lose a nut!
Beach bowling, you know what I mean?
We caught it, look!
They're gonna be trolling this place for six months looking for dead bodies!
I think he's dangerous.
He's not crazy...
but he's dangerous.
You don't think he's crazy?
No, he's not crazy.
Dr. Songee?
I don't think he's overly psychotic.
But I still think he's quite sick.
-Do you think he's dangerous?  -Absolutely so.
Well, John, what do you want to do with him?
I think we've had our turn.
I'd like to send him back to the work farm, frankly.
Is there anybody that you have...
on your staff, that could...
relate to him? Maybe understand him.
Help him out with some of these problems?
Well, the funny thing is that the person that he's the closest to...
is the one he dislikes the most.
That's you, Mildred.
Well, gentlemen, in my opinion,
if we send him back to Pendleton or...
we send him up to Disturbed...
it's just one more way of passing on our problem to somebody else.
You know, we don't like to do that.
So I'd like to keep him on the ward.
I think we can help him.
Chief, Chief, come on.
Come with me, huh?
Chief, this is the spot.
Right there is the spot. Remember?
Raise the hands, in the basket.
That's it. Raise the hands up.
All right! Let's have a little ball from you nuts in here! Here we go!
All right! Let's play some ball, nuts.
Let's make some moves!
Hey, Mac, Mac. Time, time, time.
You got six men on the court.
Harding, out of the ball game.
Hey, why me?
Because I'm the coach. I'll put you in later.
I don't trust you.
Mac... I'll go.
Okay, good boy, Billy. I'll put you in in a minute, all right?
All right, let's play ball. Harding, break over.
All right, Martini, get it back. Back!
I'm in the open! What are you doing?
You threw the goddamn ball into the fence!
Christ Almighty, you threw the ball into the fence!
There's nobody there! We're playing ball!
All right, come on, get in the game.
Defense, nobody's doing nothing here!
-For Christ's sake!  -Hey, Mac, I'm open! I'm open!
All right, Harding, give it back. Back to me, Harding! Here.
I'm open. Harding, will you give me the ball?
-Stop dribbling the goddamn ball!  -I got it!
Harding, over here.
Oh, for Christ's sake. I'm standing...
-You were covered!  -I was open!
-Just give me the ball. -They're making all over the...
I was open. Give me the ball.
You were covered, Mac.
I wasn't covered. Somebody get back!
Give it to me! Give it to me!
Chief! Thatta baby, put it in!
Get down there!
Get down there, Chief! All right, all right.
Get around, Chief!
No, no, no. Get down there, Chief!
The ball's in play! Ball's in play!
Oh, fuck that shit! You got to be crazy.
-Man, that doesn't go!  -Get that ball in play!
Come on, Chief. Put it in!
What a ball club!
McMurphy, get off the side.
-Come on, move it, man!  -Hey, dammit!
Quick! Come on, go ahead.
Go ahead.
I'll be seeing you on the outside. You know what I mean?
By the time you get out of here...
you'll be too old to even get it up.
Sixty-eight days, buddy.
Sixty-eight days.
What the fuck you talking about, 68 days?
That's in jail, sucker.
You still don't know where you're at?
Yeah, where am I at, Washington?
With us, baby, you're with us.
And you're gonna stay with us until we let you go.
Do you want to say something to the group, Mr. McMurphy?
I'd like to know why none of the guys never told me that you...
Miss Ratched...
and the doctors could keep me here
till you're good and ready to turn me loose.
That's what I'd like to know.
Fine, Randall, that's a good start.
Would anyone care to answer Mr. McMurphy?
Answer what?
You heard me, Harding.
You let me go on hassling Nurse Ratched here...
knowing how much I had to lose and you never told me nothing!
Now, Mac, wait a minute.
Wait a minute, I didn't know anything about how much...
-Shit!  -Wait a minute. Listen.
Now, look...
I'm voluntary here, see? I'm not committed.
I don't have to stay here. I mean, I can go home anytime I want.
You can go home anytime you want?
-That's it.  -You're bullshitting me!
He's bullshitting me, right?
No, Randall, he's telling you the truth.
As a matter of fact, there are very few men here who are committed.
There's Mr. Bromden.
Mr. Taber.
Some of the chronics, and you.
Cheswick?
You're voluntary?
Scanlon?
Billy, for Christ's sake, you must be committed, right?
No, no, no...
You're just a young kid!
What are you doing here? You ought to be out in a convertible...
bird-dogging chicks and banging beaver.
What are you doing here, for Christ's sake?
What's so funny about that?
Jesus, I mean, you guys do nothing but complain about how you can't...
stand it in this place here, and then you haven't got the guts to walk out?
What do you think you are, for Christ's sake? Crazy or something?
Well, you're not. You're not!
You're no crazier than the average asshole
out walking around on the streets.
And that's it.
Jesus Christ, I can't believe it!
Those are very challenging observations you made, Randall.
I'm sure some of the men would like to comment.
Mr. Scanlon?
I want to know why the dorm is locked
in the daytime and on weekends.
I would like to know about our cigarettes.
May I have my cigarettes, please, Miss Ratched?
You sit down, Mr. Cheswick, and wait your turn.
Go ahead, sit down!
To answer your question about the dorm, Mr. Scanlon...
You know very well...
that if we left the door open,
you'd just go right back to bed after breakfast.
Am I right?
So what?
May I have my cigarettes, please, Miss Ratched?
Forget the cigarettes, Cheswick.
Cigarettes are not important. Sit down, will you?
For Christ's sake!
Cigarettes!
Remember, Mr. Scanlon, we've discussed many times...
that time spent in the company of others is very therapeutic.
While time spent brooding alone only increases a feeling of separation.
You remember that, don't you?
Do you mean to say...
it's sick to want to be off by yourself?
Miss Ratched?
Mr. Cheswick, you sit down!
-Yes, but I want to know about...  -Sit down, Mr. Cheswick.
I want to...
Give him a cigarette, will you, Harding?
It's my last one.
That's a fucking lie. Why don't you give him a cigarette?
Look, I'm not running a charity ward, see?
Come on!
Look, I don't want his cigarettes.
And I don't want his, or his, or his...
or his, or his, or his...
Or even yours.
Do you understand that?
I want my cigarettes, Miss Ratched!
I want my cigarettes!
I want mine, Miss Ratched!
What gives you the damn right...
to keep our cigarettes piled up on your desk...
and to squeeze out a pack only when you feel like it, huh?
-Miss Ratched!  -Mr. Harding!
Oh, I'm sorry...
You surprise me.
I lost my head. I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, I didn't mean to...
I'm really very sorry. I just forgot.
I didn't mean to. I'm really very sorry. Just forgot.
It's all right.
Miss Ratched!
Yes, Mr. Cheswick?
I asked you a question!
I heard your question, Mr. Cheswick...
and I will answer your question as soon as you've calmed down.
Are you calm, Mr. Cheswick?
-I'm calm.  -Good.
Now, as you all know, Mr. McMurphy...
has been running a small gambling casino in our tub room.
Now, most of you lost all your cigarettes to Mr. McMurphy...
not to mention a tidy sum of money to Mr. McMurphy.
And that's why...
your tub room privileges have been suspended...
and your cigarettes have been rationed.
Mr. Martini?
How are we gonna win our money back?
You're not going to win your money back, Mr. Martini.
That's all over.
If you had obeyed the rules in the first place...
you wouldn't have lost your money.
Sit down, gentlemen! Sit down, gentlemen! Sit down!
Rules?
Piss on your fucking rules, Miss Ratched!
Sit down, will you, Cheswick?
I want you to know something right here and now, Miss Ratched!
-I ain't no little kid! I ain't no little kid!  -You sit down!
When you're gonna have cigarettes kept from me like cookies...
And I want something done! Ain't that right, Mac?
That's right! Will you sit down?
No, I won't! I won't!
I want something done!
-Sit down!  -I want something done!
-Here!  -I want something done!
Goddamn it, Cheswick, here!
Hey, calm down!
Why don't you leave him alone, Washington? He's gonna be all right!
Emergency...
I'll break your fucking back!
Forget it, Mac! It's all over, McMurphy!
Warren!
Would you move, please? We need this chair.
Just move right over there, okay.
I see we have Mr. Bromden back. Yeah, okay.
-How do you do, Mr. McMurphy?  -I do real fine.
I know you didn't do anything wrong. Just sit down.
We're not going to hurt you. Sit down, right here.
That's it.
Nurse, this is Mr. Cheswick. He's a little upset.
Okay, fine. Thank you very much.
-You'll be okay, Mr. Cheswick.  -Yes.
Would you keep an eye on these two?
Would you please take these, gentlemen?
He can't hear nothing.
Calm down, Ches, will you?
Mr. Cheswick, would you please follow me?
Mr. Cheswick?
-No!  -Nobody's gonna hurt you, come on.
-No!  -It'll be all right. Come on.
You're all right. No one's gonna hurt you.
No, leave me alone!
-Take it easy on yourself. Come on!  -No!
Mac! Mac!
No!
Come on. Come on, now. Come on.
-Come on.  -No!
I didn't do nothing!
Mac!
-Come on.  -I won't go! I don't want to go!
Want some gum?
Thank you.
Juicy Fruit.
You sly son of a bitch, Chief.
Can you hear me, too?
Yeah, you bet!
Well, I'll be goddamned, Chief!
And they all, they all think you're deaf and dumb.
Jesus Christ!
You fooled them, Chief.
You fooled them. You fooled them all!
Goddamn you!
What are we doing in here, Chief?
What's us, two guys, doing in this fucking place?
Let's get out of here...
Out.
Canada?
Canada.
We'll be there before these sons of bitches know what hit them.
Listen to Randall on this one.
Mr. McMurphy?
Please follow me.
You and me, Chief.
Take a cigarette break, boys. Easy.
I'll be fine.
Would you sit up, please?
-I'd love to.  -Thatta boy.
There might be a little fluid in them boots, you know what I mean, boys?
Just a little leak.
A light shine, boys, and...
send the specimen to Nurse Ratched.
All right, out with your gum...
Out with your gum.
Okay, this won't hurt, and it'll be over in just a moment.
-What's that?  -Conductant.
A little dab will do you.
Right, Mr. Jackson?
Open your mouth...
-What's that?  -This'll keep you from biting your tongue...
Now just bite down on it.
That's right. Just bite down.
Now, bite down on it.
Are you ready?
Here we go.
Now, one big breath.
Very good.
Gentlemen, I'd like to begin today. It shouldn't take too long.
Jim?
It's been brought to my attention...
that you've been giving Mr. Fredrickson your medication.
Is that true?
No, ma'am.
Jim?
Are you giving your medication to Mr. Fredrickson...
or are you not?
How about it, you creeps, you lunatics, mental defectives.
Let's hear it for Bullgoose Randall, back in action.
Nice shirt, Cheseroo.
Look at the faces on you!
Look at you!
The feeb's brigade, you ding-a-lings?
The mental defective league in formation.
How are you, Nurse Ratched? I'm happy to be back.
We're happy to have you back, Randall.
Thank you.
Would you like to rest today, or would you like to join the group?
I'd love to join the group...
I'd like...
I'm proud to join the group, Mildred.
How's it going, Mac?
Perfect, Billy Boy, absolutely perfect.
They was giving me 10,000 watts a day, you know, and I'm...
hot to trot.
The next woman takes me on
is gonna light up like a pinball machine...
and pay off in silver dollars!
That's an amusing thought, Randall...
but when you came in we were talking to Jim.
He has a problem with his medication...
and we'd like to get back to that.
Oh, I don't. I don't mind at all, Nurse Ratched, I'm...
gentle as a puppy dog and...
Please proceed. Thank you.
Good night, gentlemen. See you in the morning.
Yeah, baby, it's Mac.
It's on tonight.
Don't worry about it.
Don't worry about it. Get a car.
I don't give a shit, baby. Steal it if you have to.
I gotta go! I gotta go!
Don't forget to bring some booze.
Right.
Bye.
Chief, I can't take it no more.
I gotta get out of here.
I can't. I just can't.
It's easier than you think, Chief.
For you, maybe. You're a lot bigger than me.
Why, Chief, you're about as big as a goddamn tree trunk.
My poppa's real big.
He did like he pleased.
That's why everybody worked on him.
The last time I've seen my father
he was blind in the cedars from drinking.
And every time he put the bottle to his mouth...
he don't suck out of it.
It sucks out of him until he'd shrunk so...
wrinkled and yellow, even the dogs don't know him.
Killed him, huh?
I'm not saying they killed him.
They just worked on him, the way they're working on you.
There they are, Chief.
There they are. They're here.
Over here. That's it!
McMurphy, stop all this Holy Roller shit...
and get your ass back in bed. Do you understand?
My prayers have been answered, Turkle.
Come on and see.
You'd take $20...
to get down on your knees and pray, wouldn't you, Turkle?
No, it don't send me, don't send me.
-It don't?  -Don't do nothing to me, no.
Well, you know there'll be more...
I mean, they'll be bringing a couple of bottles with them, and...
You're getting closer, brother. You're getting closer, but...
they're gonna be sharing more than just bottles, ain't they?
-You know what I mean?  -Yeah, sure.
-I know what you mean.  -You understand what I mean?
Yeah, I understand what you mean.
-Anything you say, Turkle.  -I'm on my knees, brother.
-I'm on my knees.  -Yeah, all right, all right.
-Let me just give them a hand here.  -I appreciate that.
Ladies!
Oh, thank you. I believe this is your department, Mr. Turkle.
-Hi, there! Give me a hand.  -Hi, Rose, how you doing?
Love to give you a hand.
Keep it down. Keep it down.
-I split my pants.  -Keep it down!
-Give it to me. Give it all to me.  -You got to keep it down!
This looks like my high school.
Oh, hey, I take that.
-The barber chair.  -You may have it.
It is mine, mine.
You can have it. You can have it, honey.
-Take a load of these tubs.  -It's a real nice place you got here.
Hey, can I take a bath?
Sure, you can take a bath. Sure.
Just don't drown your pretty little self.
You know...
Rose was married to a maniac once, up in Beaverton.
Oh, really, miss?
What seemed to be the problem?
Oh, nothing, he used to put frogs in my bra all the time.
Very interesting.
Rose is very interested in hospitals, and hospital facilities.
-I am?  -Yes. Oh, yes, you are.
-I'm going to take Miss Candy...  -Where you going?
I'm gonna take Candy for a stroll.
I got you, I got you.
-But just don't make too much noise.  -Oh, no, not a peep, not a peep.
Now, you come over here, baby, right over here.
Don't worry about Candy, honey. Sit down and relax.
Wake up, boys.
Wake up.
It's medication time.
Medication time.
The nighttime spirits are here.
It's Randall to say goodbye...
and get you high, and nighttime angel, Candy.
That's right, Mr. Martini, there is an Easter bunny.
Round the side, boys, join Mr. McMurphy...
in the executive lounge, please.
Round the side.
It's gonna be so great.
You like a nip, don't you, Charles?
-We gonna get in trouble.  -No trouble at all!
It's Billy the Club of the fabulous and fantastic 14...
-What the hell's going on?  -Mr. Turkle...
Ain't this a bitch!
McMurphy, what you trying to do? Get my ass really fired, man?
Come on, get your ass out of here. Come on.
We're just having a party.
Party, my ass! This ain't no nightclub, this is a hospital.
Man, this is my fucking job.
I don't give a damn, this is my fucking job.
Oh, shit! The supervisor!
Come on, get your asses back in there.
Come on. Come on there!
Where is that no-talking son of a bitch? Is he in there?
Good. Come on.
Mr. Turkle?
Where the hell is he? Why doesn't he answer?
He's jerking off somewhere.
Ain't nobody jerking off nowhere, motherfucker!
Turkle, what the fuck are you doing here? Go out there and talk to her.
Doing the same fucking thing you're doing in here, hiding!
Yes, ma'am?
Everything all right, Mr. Turkle?
Oh, everything is just fine, ma'am.
Just fine. Just fine.
Who's there?
Ain't nobody in there.
Please open that door.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, ma'am, but...
you know, a man gets awfully lonesome at night...
You understand what I mean, don't you?
You understand? I'm sure you understand.
I want that woman off this ward, immediately.
Yes, ma'am.
-Jesus!  -Mr. Turkle, is she gone?
Shit! Yes, she's gone, and so am I...
so get your behinds on out of here and go back to bed.
Go ahead, move it, move it! Move it!
-I knew we were in trouble!  -Come on, let's go!
You and your teddy bear ass! Move them on out of here!
Come on, come on!
-Candy?  -Come on, Candy!
Jesus Christ!
Mr. Turkle, I'm really sorry.
Tell the fucking friends of mine to get out!
-Get out!  -I'm really sorry.
What are you...?
What the fuck...? Get out of here!
Please get out, this is my job! You fucking it up! You understand?
Get out!
Get out of here, you slim motherfucker!
Fuck it!
Good night, good night, don't let the cooties bite.
Right out of the shock department. I got it from...
I got it from Ratched's charts.
Right. There you go, there you go. Easy now.
Don't take it all at once!
Let's try a little over here. There you go.
Let's go.
I'll have to be the one, Chief.
Hey, Mac, what's going on?
Well, Dale...
Lord Randall is stepping down one.
Fredrickson.
Jimmy.
Aren't you gonna say goodbye to me, Mac?
Sure, I'm gonna say goodbye to you, Charles.
Thank you, Mac.
Thank you.
I'll never forget you.
Settle down, Charles, all right.
Hey, Billy, what's wrong?
Billy, for Christ's sake?
What's the matter?
I'm gonna miss you very...
very, very much, Mac.
Why don't you come with us, then?
Think I don't want to?
Well, so come on then, let's go.
Well, it's not that easy.
I'm not ready yet.
Tell you what we'll do...
When I get to Canada, I'll write you a postcard...
and I'll put my address on it.
That way when you're ready, you'll...
you'll know where to go.
What do you say?
She going with you?
Candy?
Yeah, she'll be there when you get there. She's going with us.
Are you gonna marry her?
No, we're just good friends.
Why?
Nothing.
Don't "nothing" me, all right? What is it?
It's too late.
Do you want a date with her?
Jesus, I must be crazy to be in a looney bin like this!
Date, huh?
Well, it'll have to be a fast date, I'll tell you that.
Not now.
Not now?
When, then?
When I have a free weekend.
You busy right now, are you?
You got something to do right now?
-You go something to do?  -No...
Good, then don't talk to me about when you're ready. Yeah, yeah.
-Ready and everything like that.  -No.
Candy, come here a minute.
Candy, I want you to meet the famous Billy.
Go get him, will you?
Go get him. Get him out of there.
I want you to get a hold of Billy.
All you gotta do is this one little thing.
-The kid's cute, isn't he?  -Yeah.
Think of me the whole time.
There he is.
Billy the Club!
I got $25...
that says you are gonna burn this woman down!
Candy, baby...
I love ya.
Hurl the ringer.
Take it easy! Back on!
No, no, no, I'll show you some card tricks.
You ain't seen the Spanish deck yet.
That's 40 percent more torture.
I'm gonna present you with this fine deck of cards for playing.
This ain't gonna take long, Rose, you know what I mean?
When we get to Canada...
Out of sight, man!
Out of sight!
-Good morning.  -Good morning.
Mr. Warren...
close the window, and lock the screen.
Right.
Mr. Miller, show this woman the way out of the hospital.
Gladly.
Come on, lady, let's go.
-You're going home.  -Where?
Let her go, Scanlon.
You're going home.
-Mr. Washington?  -Yes, Miss Ratched.
Make sure no one is missing.
Will do.
-Mac?  -Come on, Scanlon, let's move.
-Everybody out of here!  -Come on, move it out!
Come on, move it!
Martini, get your butt up! Come on, up!
All right, Colonel, get your dead ass up there!
What the hell's going on here? Come on, move out!
Miss Ratched?
Fredrickson, what are you doing?
Where you going? Back out of here!
Let's go! Come on, move it!
Taber, get up. Come on.
I said, get up!
All right, move it back there! McMurphy...
get your ass over here, and bring Dracula with you.
Stay right there, Bancini!
-Miss Ratched?  -Yes.
It looks like Billy Bibbit's the only one missing.
Billy?
Thank you, Mr. Washington.
Did Billy Bibbit leave the grounds of the hospital, gentlemen?
I want an answer to my question.
Did he leave the grounds of the hospital?
-Mr. Washington?  -Yes.
Miss Pilbow, check all the rooms.
-Mr. Warren?  -Yes.
You start with the tub room.
Mr. Martini?
May I have my cap, please?
My cap!
There.
Thank you.
Miss Ratched.
I can explain everything.
Please do, Billy.
Explain everything.
Everything?
Aren't you ashamed?
No, I'm not.
You know, Billy, what worries me is...
how your mother's going to take this.
Well, you...
don't have to...
tell her, Miss Ratched.
I don't have to tell her?
Your mother and I are old friends, you know that.
Please...
don't...
tell my mother.
Don't you think you should have thought of that
before you took that woman...
in that room?
No, no.
I didn't.
You mean, she dragged you in there by force?
She did.
Everybody did.
Everybody? Who did?
You tell me who did!
Murphy.
Miss Ratched...
please don't...
-Mr. Warren?  -tell my mother, please.
Would you see that the men are washed and ready for the day.
Miss Ratched, please...please...
-Mr. Washington?  -Yes?
-Put Billy in Dr. Spivey's office.  -No!
Stay with him till the doctor arrives.
Move it! Come on, Martini, get on!
Hey, that way, please. Please, gentlemen.
Let's go, come on. Come on, you guys. What is this?
Let's go.
Hey, what the hell is that?
McMurphy, what the hell are you doing?
Washington, to the day room! Lmmediately!
Put down those keys and nobody gets hurt.
Move away from the window and take that damn Chief with you.
Come on, let's go!
Let me through!
Out of the way, McMurphy!
Come on, clear it!
Get these people out of here!
Oh, Billy!
Will you guys clear the door?
Everybody out! Out! Everybody out!
Come on, goddammit!
Now calm down!
The best thing we can do is go on with our daily routine.
All right?
Don't! Mac!
Mac! No!
And the bets are placed.
There's one for Tabes, and Chessy, and Martini, and the dealer.
And a four to Tabes, and a six, and a nine...
and a ten to the dealer.
A nine?
What do you say, Tabes?
A dime a piece.
No? You stick.
-He sticks.  -He sticks with a four.
Chessy's going for the ride.
What does that mean?
He wants a hit. Yeah, and a big queen.
I think you're busted.
Buggered, not busted.
-Turn them over.  -Buggered.
And weep.
Hit me.
I think you're over.
-I know you're over.  -Hovno.
-That's a three.  -Hovno.
Mr. Sefelt?
Did everything go well?
That's very nice.
Now you feel better, don't you?
Yes, ma'am.
McMurphy is out.
McMurphy has escaped.
They were taking him through the tunnel.
He beat up two of the attendants and escaped.
McMurphy's upstairs.
Oh, no, no, no!
Jim, I'm telling you, McMurphy is upstairs...
and he's as meek as a lamb.
Really?
I mean, how do you know?
Jack Dunphy told me.
Jack Dunphy's full of shit!
Right! Right!
They said you escaped.
I knew you wouldn't leave without me.
I was waiting for you.
Now we can make it, Mac.
I feel big as a damn mountain.
Oh, no!
I'm not going without you, Mac.
I wouldn't leave you here this way.
You're coming with me.
Let's go!